And now we come to the $64,000 question.
Are we alone?
Obviously, in explaining to you that I
have been channeling an extraterrestrial
consciousness for 40 years, I believe we
are not alone.
Our society has recently expanded its
ideas about extraterrestrials.
In the past few years, we have
discovered literally thousands of extra
solar planets around other stars. And
we're beginning to realize that this is
the rule rather than the exception.
Now, not all of those planets are
capable of harboring life as we know it.
But calculations have been made that
would admit that there probably are at
least thousands, if not tens of
thousands or even millions of planets
that are capable of harboring life as we
know it throughout the universe.
But the question that a lot of people
have is not so much is there life out
there because most people at this point
would admit that it's probably
ridiculous to think that in the entire
universe there is no other life at all.
The question really is but are they
here? Have they traveled to Earth?
Obviously, there have been just
thousands upon thousands of what are
called UFO sightings or what are now
referred to as UAP sightings across the
globe for a long, long time. And some of
those sightings,
some of which I've had myself, are
irrefutable
as machines that fly through the air.
They're not mysterious lights in the
distance. Many people have seen UFOs up
close and personal and cannot deny what
they've seen any more than they could
deny seeing an airplane in the sky or a
helicopter at close range. So the
question is, are these really
extraterrestrial craft? Are they craft
that come from our own planet? Advanced
technological craft from our own
government or some other foreign
government.
So the idea is to understand how these
UFOs operate and to understand that they
are still doing things that are at least
as far as we know beyond our technical
capability.
The idea also extends into what are
called contact events or encounter
events or even into the realm that is
known as alien abduction.
And in that realm, most people report
seeing a certain kind of
extraterrestrial that has become known
as the grays. Now, Bashar has a very
unique story about who the grays are and
why they're here and doing what it is
they're doing in these so-called
abductions.
The idea for him is not so much that the
grays are truly alien, but that they
come from a parallel reality
and that in their parallel reality long
ago, they used to be as human as we are.
That they were more technologically
minded, more advanced, but also perhaps
a little bit behind in the spirituality
department. They took for granted the
idea as many humans on this earth are
doing of their connection to nature.
Didn't really honor their connection to
nature and eventually really destroyed
their ecosystem,
destroyed their forests, destroyed their
oceans, destroyed the atmosphere with
their technology.
It reached a tipping point according to
Bashar's story that was finally too late
to reverse.
As humans, they could not survive in
their normal fashion. They had to go
underground. They had to create
underground cities and colonies in order
to filter out the pollutants from their
world. But it wasn't good enough.
Eventually, they found that they could
no longer reproduce because the
pollutants had entered their system to
the point where they could not be
exised. And they lost a lot of their
normal abilities. They began to realize
that their species was dying out on
their version of Earth was becoming a
wasteland.
So they had to start mutating themselves
to adapt to the environment more and
more. And they became ultimately used to
living underground,
gained more and more abilities of being
able to survive that way, enlarged their
eyes to see in the dark, and became the
beings ultimately over generations that
we know now as the grays.
The idea is they knew that they were
dying out and even cloning wasn't going
to help them continue their
civilization.
So according to Bashar's story, they
used their advanced technology to tunnel
into different parallel realities,
different versions of Earth that existed
alongside theirs where human DNA was
still viable, such as our reality.
And they chose to take human DNA,
extract it from people that they had
abducted in order to blend it with their
genetics, and create a hybrid race or
several hybrid races that would allow
their civilization to survive.
Based on some of the information that I
originally talked about where long ago
another ET race called the Anunnaki
created Homo sapiens by injecting their
genetics into the naturally evolved
homminid called Homo erectus creating a
hybrid species called Homo sapiens. Now
this represents the idea of a second
generation of hybridization of the human
species by the grays to create these
hybrids that would not only perpetuate
their civilization
but in return as a gift for the gift we
have given them of continuing to exist.
The hybrids themselves such as Bashar's
civilization
are willing to see us as family. They're
connected to us genetically and are
willing to give us the information that
they have been giving us for the past
four decades and longer to help us avoid
the same pitfalls and the same result
that destroyed the gray civilization
because they recognize we're doing many
of the same things that the grays
ultimately did to destroy their version
of Earth. So in applying this
information from Bashar
to our lives, we can seek better paths,
more constructive avenues, more positive
ways of doing things so that we do not
follow the grays in their destruction of
their version of Earth.
Now, one of the questions, one of the
main questions people have about whether
or not ETSs can reach Earth is the idea
of the great and vast distances between
the stars.
We do understand that there may be life
out there, but many people simply do not
believe that it can reach us. That no
technology can actually make it possible
from spanning these vast gulfs of
distance between different star systems.
Well, but more recently, even our own
scientists, a few of them have realized
that there are ways around this idea.
There are ways around this shortcoming.
and that while they can prove
mathematically that it is possible to go
to a different star system in a
relatively short amount of time, the
math works for those equations. They say
that the only impediment is that we
simply now don't have the technology to
do so. But a civilization a 100 years, a
thousand years, 10,000 years ahead of
ours might have solved these problems of
technology, might have different ways of
understanding how to travel from star to
star in a relatively quick amount of
time. Bashar has explained the way that
his civilization does this. And without
going into great detail in putting it in
simple terms, here is what he said works
for them.
We consider an object to exist in a
location in space and time. But they
don't think of it that way. They say
that every object has a certain
frequency to it. It is made up of
different patterns of energy. They can
look at those patterns of energy almost
as an equation.
One part of that equation is the
object's location in space and time. So
they don't see an object as existing in
space and time. They see location as
part of the description of an object.
They have developed the ability to reach
in and change that locationational
variable in the equation that makes up
that object such as a spaceship. And by
changing its locationational variable,
they can change it from location A to
location B by mapping out the universe
as a variety of different spatial
coordinates and by imposing a spatial
coordinate on their spaceships and the
crew within to represent a location at a
far distant star. And by truly
overwhelming the energy of that object,
then they can allow that object to
disappear from location A and suddenly
take up residence at location B without
actually having traveled the intervening
distance. It's really like a
instantaneous relocation of that idea.
Again, going back to the holographic
principle that everything actually
exists everywhere in the universe and
it's simply by imposing a certain
vibration upon it that causes it to
manifest at one location as opposed to
the location that it previously
occupied. This is an extremely advanced
technology. They are thousands of years
ahead of us. But it makes it possible
for civilizations that have mastered
those kinds of technologies to instantly
travel from one star to another easily
and therefore to visit planets such as
Earth and to be seen as the UFOs in our
skies. Bashar has said that one day
after open contact occurs, we also will
learn to master these kinds of
technologies and that one day we will
travel to other planets and we will
become their UFOs and they will wonder
about us and we may be able to help them
reach a new age of understanding of life
in the galaxy, life in the universe and
allow us to present them with the
possibility of open contact as Bashar is
presenting this possibility to us.
Now, the other thing I would like to
talk about because we're talking about
soul's journey here and spiritual
journeys is the idea that we are not
only not alone with regard to physical
extraterrestrials,
but we are never alone anyway because we
have connections to spirit, we have
spirit guides, we have soul families.
The idea is for us to know that they are
always there to help us when we really
need it and for us to know that we are
always receiving that help even though
we may not always be aware of it. So the
very question of are we alone can be
answered not only on a physical but also
on a spiritual level and the answer is
no. We have a lot of help going on. And
the idea of praying for guidance, the
idea of asking for help is not so much
the idea of asking for something that we
don't have. The idea of asking for help
is to be in a state of grace, a state of
allowance, a state of gratitude and
appreciation to be able to be more aware
of the help that we are already always
receiving. So the idea is to not think
of that we are alone but to really
understand that we have probably never
ever been alone.
So to talk about the idea of where these
extraterrestrials are that are visiting
us. Bashar of course is from a
civilization that he has described very
often in the channelings that I do. The
planet in their ancient language is
called Esasani and it means place of
living light. Their planet is not unlike
Earth, but it's much greener, has a
little bit more water, more oxygen. We
could survive there if we made a shift
into their parallel reality and landed
on their planet. And the idea is that we
might be a little bit dizzy at first
because of the extra oxygen, but we
could adapt to it. We could get used to
it. Now, he said that their planet is
left very green. They don't really have
a lot of builtup cities or structures on
the planet, except temporary ones that
may serve a temporary purpose. Their
spaceships are their cities, and some of
their spaceships are quite large, what
you might call mother ships or city
ships that can actually hold hundreds of
thousands of people. However, the
population on their planet is nowhere
near what it is on Earth. At any given
time, the population of Essasani may not
exceed about 300 million individuals.
But the idea is that some are living on
the planet, some are in ships exploring
different things. And Bashar
specifically presents himself as a first
contact specialist,
which means it is his passion to go and
explore and meet different
civilizations, to make contact with
different alien species in different
planets and different dimensions and to
explore the possibility of them joining
in a sense their interstellar alliance
or to simply have some form of
relationship that expands everyone. This
is why they're excited about interacting
with Earth. We do things very
differently than they do. They are
learning from us different ways that
beings have of expressing themselves in
the same way we may be learning things
from him. And to them, this expands the
galactic family that we belong to and
that they belong to. Now, he has talked
about some different civilizations. He's
talked about civilizations that exist in
the SAR system of Sirius. He's talked
about civilizations that exist in the
star systems that we label as Orion.
He's talked about the Plleades star
systems as having habitable planets in
it. He's talked about the Lyren systems
also. And he's talked about other
dimensional beings that may exist beyond
our physical understanding of reality,
but nonetheless may be interacting with
levels of our consciousness that we may
be unaware of. Or we may encounter in
dream experiences when our physical
minds are out of the way and our spirit
selves are more open to receiving
connections and communications from
beings that don't have any kind of
similarity to us as a physical being. So
there are many different civilizations
that Bashar has talked about. He's
saying that in terms of their
interstellar alliance, there is well
over at least 200 civilizations that
belong to it. And that there are many,
many thousands of civilizations that
populate our galaxy alone, let alone the
other galaxies in our universe, let
alone the galaxies that may exist in
parallel realities. So we are far from
alone. The universe in a sense is
teameming with life. And if we are
willing to open up to the idea of
contact with other civilizations, we
will know very quickly that we are
certainly not alone.
So with regard to open contact,
why is this a matter of discussion now?
Why is this important? Even our own
government has begun to admit that UFOs
actually do exist. They have been
captured on cameras, on planes, and all
sorts of ways. We're beginning to start
to open up to look at this phenomena as
a real phenomena that deserves a little
bit more investigation, perhaps a lot
more investigation.
Bashar has said that in a sense that
when we started thinking about life on
other planets that it might be more
possible. We kind of sent out an energy
invitation to them and they responded to
it. This is the way that they usually
initiate contact with other
civilizations is by finding some
individuals that they can send
information through and they observe
what people do with that information in
that civilization. whether they accept
it and apply it, whether they reject it,
and they use that as a barometer for
whether or not open contact is something
that that civilization wants because
they leave it up to us. They leave it in
our hands to decide whether that's where
we want to go. They don't want to
interfere with our civilization. They
want us to make the decision as to
whether that's something that is
beneficial for us. They are willing to
interact with us, but only at our true
invitation. So the idea is he is sensing
that more and more people are exploring
the expansion of consciousness. More and
more people are aware that life is
possible on other planets. More and more
people are exploring their own spiritual
journeys.
This opens up the avenue for more of
these discussions. It brings us closer
to their vibration. And when we meet
them halfway is when Bashar said then
open contact is possible. Now Bashar
rarely makes predictions because he has
said in a sense there's no such thing as
a prediction of the future. There is a
sensing by certain people of the energy
that exists at the moment the prediction
is made. And if that energy doesn't
change, then the prediction can come to
pass. If the prediction makes itself
known in a way that people don't want
that to happen, they can change the
energy and the prediction will become
obsolete. That doesn't mean the initial
prediction was wrong. It just means that
the energy of the moment that the
prediction was made has changed and now
we've gone down a different path. But
now and then Bashar will make a
prediction when he feels that the
momentum and the energy behind the
prediction is so strong that it's
unlikely to change. For example, in
1998,
and this was recorded on tape, Bashar
said that it was very probable that
there would be a terrorist attack on New
York before the end of 2001. Obviously,
that has come to pass. He has said
before the 2016 election that after it
in the United States, everything would
change. I think many people would agree
that has come to pass. The most recent
prediction he has been willing to make
that he feels is unlikely to shift is he
has said there is over a 90% probability
that by the end of 2026 or the beginning
of 2027 there will be some sort of
contact event that would be relatively
undeniable. He is not saying why that
happens. He's not saying what causes it
to happen. He is simply saying that at
that point there is a high degree of
probability that people on Earth will
understand and know that
extraterrestrial life does exist. That
contact is potentially possible. We will
have to wait and see exactly what events
may bring that about and whether or not
that prediction comes to pass. But as I
said, it's rare for him to make such
predictions and the others that he has
made in the past have in fact happened.
So we will altogether wait and see if
this is an opportunity for us to open up
to the possibility of open contact. But
they will be watching to see what we do
with that event, whatever it is and
however it unfolds because our reactions
and our responses to it are what's going
to tell them whether we are ready or
not. For example, there is a very famous
UFO sighting called the Phoenix Lights
that took place back in the late '90s
that happened where a large mileong
craft passed very slowly over the state
of Arizona and was witnessed by more
than 10,000 individuals. There was
hardly any mention of it on the news
unless there was being passed off as
flares or planes or lights from balloons
or something like that.
how we responded to that, denying that
that happened, denying 10,000 witnesses
was an indication to Bashar and other
extraterrestrials that are observing
Earth that we simply were not ready for
contact yet. So we will see what happens
if this event occurs as Bashar has said
it might and we will see what our
response is and more importantly the AS
will see what our response is and that
will determine how quickly open contact
on Earth might occur.
Now, in light of all that's been said,
humans can play a very active role in
initiating contact. There are many
groups that are going into what they
call C5 encounters where they're going
out into certain remote areas. They are
sending up lights. They are sending up
thoughts. They are reaching out
telepathically and energetically to
invite the ETs to come and interact with
us. And some of them have had some
measure of success in getting responses
from the UFOs. People might shine
certain lights or flash certain lights
and the UFOs will flash lights back at
them in the same pattern. Things like
this are the very beginning stages of
contact. So I would encourage people to
go out to not be afraid to initiate
contact in this way because again the
more people that are willing to say yes,
we know you're here. We know you've
always been here. We're willing and
ready to accept the idea that we belong
to a bigger universe, a bigger family
than we ever thought, and we're willing
to have open contact with you, then
perhaps the faster open contact can
occur. So, by all means, use your
imaginations.
Go out, do the things that would allow
you to express your willingness to have
open contact. And ideally, the ETSs will
respond in some way, shape, or form
sooner than later.